# **Imtiaz Khan**

- 106 Heath Road, CV24PW Coventry (United Kingdom)
- (+44) 07466483865
- <u>imteiaz@gmail.com</u>
- Nhatsapp: 07466483865

**Subject:** IT Support Technician

## Dear Sir/Madam

I am writing to express my interest in the IT Specialist position at your company as advertised on Indeed. With a Certification in Information Technology, Fifteen plus years of hands-on experience in IT support and systems administration, and a strong dedication to problem-solving, I am confident in my ability to contribute effectively to your team.

In my previous role at CEA, I successfully managed the IT infrastructure for a mid-sized enterprise, ensuring seamless operation of all systems and networks. My responsibilities included troubleshooting hardware and software issues, managing server environments, and implementing security protocols to safeguard sensitive data.

My technical expertise includes proficiency in a variety of operating systems such as Windows and macOS, as well as experience with virtualization technologies like VMware. I am also skilled in using various scripting languages, including JAVA to automate routine tasks and improve system reliability. Furthermore, my strong communication skills allow me to effectively collaborate with both technical and non-technical stakeholders to deliver optimal IT solutions.

Thank you for considering my application. I look forward to the opportunity to discuss how my background, skills, and certifications make me a perfect fit for this position. Please feel free to contact me at 07466483865 or via email at Imteiaz@gmail.com to schedule an interview.

Kind regards Imtiaz Khan





# **Imtiaz Aslam Khan**

**Date of birth:** 02/02/1986 | **Gender:** Male | **Phone number:** 

(+44) 07466483865 (Mobile) | Email address: <a href="mailto:lmteiaz@gmail.com">lmteiaz@gmail.com</a>

Address: 106 Heath Road, , CV24PW, Coventry, United Kingdom (Home)

## **ABOUT ME**

I am certified IT Specialist with 15+ years of hands on experience in the IT world. I am expert in troubleshooting and resolving the problem using my hardware and software skills. Currently I am looking for a job that will challenge my abilities every new day.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

27/11/2023 - CURRENT Cirencester, United Kingdom

## **IT ACCOUNT MANAGER PHONE BOX GADGETS**

My main job responsibility includes:

- Providing IT Support to the company using my hard and soft IT Skills.
- Public relations professionals plan, organise and co-ordinate the activities that promote the image and understanding of an organisation and its products or services to consumers, businesses, members of the public and other specified audiences.

06/2023 - 11/2023 London, United Kingdom

**ICT TECHNICIAN IPROFIX CHISWICK** 

## As an ICT technician i offer my service at iProFix for Computers follow:

 Install, maintain, repair and operate information systems and any ICT related equipment (laptops, desktops, servers, tablets, smart phones, communications equipment, printers and any piece of computer related peripheral networks), and any type of software (drivers, operating systems, applications)

## As mobiles repair my daily activity include:

• Perform all aspects of the repair and maintenance on mobile phones. Excellent hand-eye coordination and ability to perform small repairs. In-depth knowledge of different models of cell phones both old and new.

04/04/2022 - 05/07/2022 Bologna, Italy

IT SPECIALIST COOPERATIVA EDILE APPENNINO S.C. A R.L.

As an IT specialist, I was responsible for providing various forms of computer-related technical assistance and improving the efficiency of the work of the staff through the use of technology.

- Performed IT support, both software and hardware for CEA employees
- Maintained IT systems with a 100% resolution rate within 24 hours
- Supported over 150+ employees help desk issues on a daily basis

05/05/2019 - 12/03/2022 Reggio Emilia, Italy

### IT TECHNICIAN AND PROGRAMMER CMAX

## In CMAX my daily activity were:

- Installation and configuring of all IT device, PC, Printers and Network Tools.
- Designed 16 major projects in Autocad
- · Managing company network.

- Responsibility of managing foregign client inquiry using gmail and other social plateform.
- I have effective communication skills to handle all types of inquiry In addition to that i was speaking more then 5 languages that makes me perfect for this position as customer support.

Website www.cmaxitaly.com

08/05/2017 - 12/12/2018 Copenhagen, Denmark

### **MOBILE PHONE REPAIR TECHNICIAN** MOBILE FIX

## My responsiblity in MOBILE FIX was

- Repairing of Apple producsts iphones, ipads etc.
- I have also developed Andriod App in Android Studio for Mobile Fix (Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=tr.dk.cph.mobilefix&gl=IT)

01/04/2012 - 04/12/2013

## **COMPUTER HARDWARE REPAIR TECHNICIAN BARGAIN COMPUTERS,**

• My jobs include Installation, configuration and ordinary hardware / software maintenance of all IT devices and replacing of damage hardware parts when necessary.

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

### **ICT TECHNICIAN** AL MASA COMPUTERS

• I was repairing client computers, troubleshooting and implementation of networks and solving computer technical issue when they occure.

### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Birmingham, United Kingdom

**BUSINESS STUDIES** Business Research Business Ethics Business HR European Business Accounting

Address Forest House 16-20 Clements Road, Ilford, Essex,, IG1 1BA, Birmingham, United Kingdom

Website https://web.empirecollege.london/

10/10/2002 - 12/09/2004 Pakistan

F.A English, mathematics, statistics and economics

Address Swat, Pakistan

## LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PASHTO** 

Other language(s): ENGLISH | ARABIC | URDU | ITALIAN

### DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Word | Microsoft Excel | Outlook | Microsoft Office | Social Media | Mobile app | Android app development in Android studio | Android app development | Html, Css, Java | AREA WEB: Web Designer, Web Developer | Web design, Web developer | Hardware | Computer Hardware | Computer Software | Basic IT Networking | Virtual assistance | Data Entry | Help Desk | CCNA | Graphics Design,

## DRIVING LICENCE

**Driving Licence:** B 29/05/2023 – 28/05/2033